Beverly Cassara Papers
Beverly Cassara Papers
- Personal papers
  - Journals
    - [bound appointment book], 1990 (Box 56)
    - [bound appointment book/desk calendar], 1991 (Box 56)
  - Medical and dental insurance (Box 56)
  - Memorabilia, oversize (Oversize 1)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1971; 1973-1976,; 1981-1982; 7 folders (Box 57)
  - Passports, birth and marriage certificates (Box 57)
  - Photographs, unidentified (Box 57)
  - Resumes, Beverly Cassara (Box 57)
  - Resumes, Ernest Cassara (Box 57)
  - "The story of 529 Webster Street", 1980-1992; BC's reminiscences of childhood, family history (Box 58)
  - Travel souvenirs and miscellany
    - England (Box 58)
    - Germany (Box 58)
    - Ireland (Box 58)
    - Spain (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous expenses and receipts (Box 58)
  - Miscellany (Box 58)
- Audiovisual material
  - Adult education class, University of Alaska, / Anchorage (Dr. Gretchen Bersch), 7 May 1996. / Presentation by Dr. Beverly Benner Cassara, cassara_060; VHS (Oversize 4)
  - Anita Hill: Race, gender and power, Maine Public Radio, 10/30/92; cassara_043; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Barry Commoner American Public Radio, 11/3/92; cassara_012; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - [Side 1] Budget Comm Meeting 5/22/72 / Freire by Gittens / Johnson -- Wilson [Side 2] Roy Chisholm, Sanders, 1972; cassara_059; very unclear what the actual title of this tape is; much of what is written appears to have been crossed out.; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Claude Touchette, cassara_055; includes a few pages of notes by BC; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Danish Folk Adult Ed Movement - Per Himmelstrup - 1, cassara_013; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Danish Folk Adult Ed Movement - Per Himmelstrup - 2, cassara_014; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Dr. Jerrold Coombs, U. of British Columbia, James Farmer & Robert Carlson, cassara_015; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - [Jimmy Carter], cassara_011; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Finnish Assoc. of Ad. Ed. [Association of Adult Education], cassara_017; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Frank Sherwood Federal Executive Institute AEA-VA, Apr 29, 1971 / Mrs. B[illegible] Overstreet AEA-VA May 1, 1971, cassara_049; Adult Education Association of Virginia?; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - German adult educators interviews
    - -----, Annette, cassara_040; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - -----, Elizabeth, cassara_041; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Dahmen, cassara_018; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Doerry, cassara_019; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Dolff, cassara_020; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Dörte, cassara_021; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Düchting, cassara_022; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Fels, cassara_023; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Kehnen, cassara_025; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Kirz, cassara_026; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Labor, cassara_027; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Lehnenn, cassara_028; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Lühr, cassara_030; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Meyer, cassara_031; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Miller, cassara_024; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Öels, cassara_032; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Perl, cassara_033; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Peters, cassara_034; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Pflüger, cassara_035; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Sausen, cassara_036; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Tafel, cassara_037; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Völker, cassara_029; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Wessler, cassara_038; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    - Witte, cassara_039; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Greiden, on his new book, approx. 21 min, cassara_042; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Harvey Wheeler Center for Study of Dem Institutions - Co-author of Fail Safe Los Angeles, Nov. 1971; cassara_056; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Khalfan Mazrui, Nov. 5, 1984; cassara_048; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Knowles - Houle #2, cassara_004; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Luis Mitchell Transcentury Speech Conference, 10/25/83; cassara_050; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Malcolm Knowles, Leonard Freedman, Nov 1971; cassara_003; Preparing adult educators for survival in a turbulent society, Dr. Leonard Freedman, Dir Ext UCLA; Malcolm Knowles at Comm. of Ad. Ed. Profs Los Angeles on history of B.Y. programs; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Manning Marable, cassara_046; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Manning Maribel [Marable] Denver, Oct 1993; cassara_047; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Martha Friedenthal-Haase, Nov 5, '84; cassara_010; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Minister of Education Finland, cassara_016; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Not Just Kid Stuff, cassara_051; audio portion of presentation; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
    For slides and script portion of this presentation, see Correspondence-subject files: Not Just Kid Stuff.
  - Onushkin Leningrad, cassara_052; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - P. Hughes [probably Patrick Hughes], cassara_044; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Patrick Hughes, International Ad. Ed. C[illegible] on World Bank, Mar 7, 1984; cassara_045; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Paulo Freire - Cecil County Community College Maryland, 1985 (Feb); cassara_002; Interview with Paulo Freire.; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Saskia (Moscow), Sept 22, 1987; cassara_053; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Symposium on Literacy and Development in the 80s - A World Perspective - tape 1, circa 1980; cassara_006; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Symposium on Literacy and Development in the 80s - A World Perspective - tape 2, circa 1980; cassara_007; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Symposium on Literacy and Development in the 80s - A World Perspective, circa 1980; cassara_008; may be duplicate of 006 or 007; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Symposium on Literacy and Development in the 80s - A World Perspective, circa 1980; cassara_009; may be duplicate of 006 or 007; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Test of Spoken English Sample Tape Item No. 277653 Educational Testing Service, 1981; cassara_054; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Women of Achievement Beverly Cassara interview, WETA, cassara_001; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - Women’s Mtg P. Hall + M. Richards / Library Chautauqua; Lyceum, cassara_005; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - A World Perspective on Lifelong Learning Paul Bertelsen - 1, cassara_057; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
  - A World Perspective on Lifelong Learning Paul Bertelsen - 2, cassara_058; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Oversize 4)
- Printed material
  - Africa, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Africa (oversize) (Oversize 2)
  - Eastern Europe (Box 59)
  - Germany, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Germany (oversize), clippings and newspapers (Oversize 1)
  - Hong Kong (Box 59)
  - Kenya, 4 folders (Box 59)
  - Kenya (oversize), clippings, newspapers, magazines, book; 3 folders (Oversize 2)
  - Middle East (Box 60)
  - [Minority file] (Oversize 1)
  - Thailand, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - United Nations Educational and Scientific Organization (UNESCO) (Box 60)
  - World Bank (Box 60)
  - Miscellany, 3 folders (Box 61)
  - Miscellany (oversize) (Oversize 1)